PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- When I was young, I really liked some sports
我小时候很喜欢一些运动
like softball and I was the catcher
比如棒球
and the first base player and I also liked music.
我是捕手和一垒 我同样也喜欢音乐
I started playing the flute in the fourth grade
我四年级开始玩横笛
and from there I played in the band
然后加入了乐队
and I branched out and taught myself tenor saxophone
然后我自学了高音萨克斯
and played that in the jazz band
又加入了爵士乐队
and I was in the marching band and the symphonic band
我还待过仪仗队和管乐队
and I was a drum major
担任指挥
and lots of different activities with music.
所以我和音乐有过甜蜜的过往
It was great.
这很棒
In high school, there were some elective classes
在高中 有一些选修课
that we need to take and my mom was helping me figure out
我妈妈帮我出了些主意
which ones to pick.
关于选择那个课
And she had gone back to school while I was a kid
在我还是孩子的时候 她还得回学校上课
and she had taken a programming class
她那时候修了一个程序课
and she suggested that I took one of those
然后她就建议我选一个这类的课
to see if I liked it and so that's how I got into it
看看我会不会喜欢
and I already liked computers, I love playing with them.
我很喜欢玩电脑
I remember my parents getting our first computer.
我爸妈给我的第一台电脑
It was an old 286
是个286（第二代因特尔微芯计算机 1982年诞生）
and it was just something that was
在当时来说
at that point a toy but then learning
他就是一个玩具 但是
how to program a computer was really interesting to me
学着如何给电脑编程令我很兴奋
and so I started taking computer classes in ninth grade
所以9年级开始 我开始学电脑课
and all through high school.
然后一直延续到整个高中结束
Yeah, I majored in computer science、
是的 我是个文科学校毕业出来的
in the liberal arts school and got a Bachelor of Science
计算机学士
and I also did a minor in mathematics.
我还辅修了数学
I got a Master's and a PhD from UC Berkeley
我在UC伯克利获得了硕士和博士学位
and my Master's was in computational geometry
硕士专业是计算机几何算法
and my thesis was on physically-based simulation
论文是关于《如何在平面上创建如同泥浆绘画般
for creating crack patterns on surfaces so like mud drawing.
的破碎图形样式的基于物理的模拟方案》
I also looked at crackle glass
我同样也研究了玻璃杯
and so that's a way to create crack patterns in class
这也就可以创建破碎的玻璃图形样式
and use that for cups and bowls and things like that.
然后引用到相应的器皿上
In my internship,
我实习的工作是
I ended up working on an inverse kinematics problem
对逆运动学进行研究（也就是所谓的IK）
with Andy Weken who was my mentor and the research group.
Andy Weken是我的导师
Let's pretend I wanna animate my arm
我们假设我要做一个我手臂的动画
and I would wanna grab my wrist and move it here
我抓着我的手腕然后移动到这儿
and what inverse kinematics does is it would solve
而逆运动学的作用就是
to figure out what are the angles
去找出为了将我的手腕移动到这儿
that I'd have to move my elbow joint and my shoulder joint
我的肩膀和手肘运动的角度是多少
to hit the target which is where my wrist is.
才能让我的手腕运动到这儿
It's really exciting for me
这对我来说非常有意思
to watch the finished movie for Brave.
在最终完成的brave电影里
I worked on a lot of the technology that was used
我贡献了很多技术支持
to animate the characters and to do the hair simulator.
被用于角色动画和毛发模拟中
I wrote the inverse kinematic system
我写了一套IK系统
that was used to move the horses and move the humans.
用来移动马和人
I spent a lot of time trying to make sure
我花了很多时间来确保
that posing tool was right and having that
这个调动画的工具可行
and have Merida's hair fill up the entire screen
而当merida的头发飘扬在荧幕里
was incredibly satisfying
我感到异常满足
and to see how beautiful it all turned out.
看看这最终效果多好
And while I was writing those tools,
当我在写这些工具的时候
I got scheduled to do an interview
我收到了一个面试的预约
with another co-worker for the simulation group
和另一个模拟部门的同事一起
because they were looking for a new simulation person
因为他们想找一个新的模拟同事
and the person who left had done
而之前离开的同事
fluids and other types of simulation work
是做流体和其它模拟的
that wasn't an area that I was familiar with
那这块儿我不熟
so I hadn't even thought about this work, this job opening
所以我压根儿没想这事儿
and I think it had been open for about a year
我以为这个职位已经在那儿悬了一年了
when we were talking about it.
当我们谈到这个问题的时候
They were having a hard time filling this position
他们说找人好难啊
and the person we were interviewing
而我们面试的这个人呢
was doing a Master's thesis
还在写硕士论文
and he was implementing some of my PhD thesis
他引用了我的一些博士论文
and so after the interview, my co-worker said,
所以当面试结束后 我同事来问我
he turned to me and said,
他转过身说道
"Why aren't you applying for this job?"
你干嘛不来应聘这个职位
That was really a point in my career
这是我职业生涯的一个很重要的点
to really sit and think like,
我得认真想想
"Huh, why I aren't I applying for this job?"
为啥我不去呢
And so I really gave it some consideration and decided
所以我认真的考虑了下
and was like, "Yeah, I do wanna apply for this job."
然后我说我挺想试试的
And it's always a little bit scary when you try to
有时候去做一件新的尝试总会有点怕怕
do something new but it was definitely worth it.
但是很值得
I didn't listen to the people that were saying,
我没去听有些人说的
"Oh, you should be doing this instead,"
你现在做的这个就很好
because you should do what your heart tells you
因为有时候你要率性一下
and even if it's scary, you should go ahead and do it.
虽千万人吾往矣
aimozhen.com/pixarinabox